<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hugo on Nico Westerbeck</title>
    <link>https://nico-westerbeck.de/tags/hugo/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hugo on Nico Westerbeck</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016 Nico Westerbeck</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 17:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://nico-westerbeck.de/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up this webspace</title>
      <link>https://nico-westerbeck.de/post/setting-up-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2016 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://nico-westerbeck.de/post/setting-up-website/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;As this was my today&amp;rsquo;s project, I will lose some words about how I set up this site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;hosting&#34;&gt;Hosting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am hosting at &lt;a href=&#34;https://uberspace.de/&#34;&gt;uberspace&lt;/a&gt;, a very hipster shared hoster, which let&amp;rsquo;s you choose your price yourself. Their hosting principle is a multi-user linux environment, where you automatically get a user assigned and some stuff provisioned. It relies on linux unprivileged users as the only isolation from other users on the same machine, so I would not recommend using the space for anything critical. However, I like the setup and how everything is documented, so I chose it as a hoster. I will just hope no other user on my machine uses a privilege escalation to put a dickbutt on my page&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But everything was up to date, so I would rate the risk as pretty low.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;website-generation&#34;&gt;Website generation&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This website is generated by &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;hugo&lt;/a&gt;, a really easy to dive in static-website generator. It creates your site by using Markdown and predefined (or self-modified) themes, putting out a ready-to-use website. It took me roughly 30 minutes to get into it, and I am really considering to use this for my next website-projects aswell. I don&amp;rsquo;t really like wordpress and other, full-blown competitors, as hacking down some markdown is just faster and more intuitive to me than using a fully fledged WYSIWYMPG-editor (What You See Is What You Might Possibly Get). Also it features a nice way to locally host a draft of the site (with live-codereloading and millisecond build times)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;deployment&#34;&gt;Deployment&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I build the files locally with &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; and transfer them, including the /public folder, to my webserver via git. I found that would be the easiest way to keep my local instance and the remote git up to date.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;dns&#34;&gt;DNS&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://namecheap.com&#34;&gt;namecheap&lt;/a&gt;, despite having a dubious name, turned out to be quite a good DNS registrar. So far I am pleased.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
